miami.edu 2016-06-21

# Privacy Statement and Legal Notices | University of Miami

Thank you for visiting the University of Miami website. The University of Miami is a private, independent, international university and an equal opportunity/affirmative action employer.

 **Non-Discrimination Policy**  
It is the policy of the University of Miami that no person within the jurisdiction thereof shall, on the basis of race, religion, color, sex, age, disability, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, veteran status, or national origin, be excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination or harassment (including all forms of sexual harassment and sexual violence) under any program or activity of the University, regardless of whether such program or activity occurs on-campus or off-campus. The University does not intend by this commitment to require compliance with this policy by governmental or external organizations that associate with but are not controlled by the University, except as required by law. The Executive Director of Equality Administration is responsible for coordinating the University’s effort to implement the nondiscrimination policy and Affirmative Action Programs for employees and students. The Director may be contacted at the following address or telephone number: Equality Administration Office, 1320 South Dixie Highway, Gables One Tower, Suite 100R, Coral Gables, FL 33146; Phone: (305) 284-3064.

**International Students**  
The University of Miami is authorized under Federal law to enroll non-immigrant alien students.

**Reserved Rights**  
The University reserves the right to change any provision or requirement, including, but not limited to fees and tuition, at any time without notice. Degrees, courses, programs, activities, and like academic or non-academic offerings of the University may also be changed from time to time without notice. The University further reserves the right to require a student to withdraw at any time under University policies, as may be promulgated from time to time. Further, admission of a student to the University of Miami for any semester does not imply that such student will be enrolled in any succeeding academic semesters. It also reserves the right to impose sanctions on any student whose conduct is unsatisfactory. Any admission on the basis of false statements or documents is void when the misconduct is discovered, and the student is not entitled to any credit for work which the student may have done at the University prior to any discipline that may be taken as a result of such misconduct. When a student is dismissed or suspended from the University for cause, there will be no refund of tuition or fees paid. If a dismissed student has paid only a part of his tuition and fees, the balance due the University will be considered a receivable and will be collected.

There will be no refund of tuition, fees, charges or any other payments made to the University in the event the operation of the University is suspended at any time as a result of any act of God, strike, riot, disruption, or for any other reason beyond the control of the University.

**Accreditation**  
The University of Miami is accredited by the Commission on Colleges of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools to award the baccalaureate, masters and doctoral degrees. Contact the Commission on Colleges at 1866 Southern Lane, Decatur, Georgia 30033-4097 or call 404-679-4500 for questions about the accreditation of the University of Miami.

**Privacy Statement  
**Your privacy is very important to us. Simply stated, our policy is to collect no personally identifiable information about you when you visit our website unless you actively choose to make such information available to us. This Privacy Statement generally describes how we collect, use and/or share information gathered by our websites.

**Information We Collect  
** When visiting our websites, some information is collected electronically or by technology. For example, when accessing the Internet, each computer is assigned a unique identifier called an IP address that identifies where information is coming from or where information should be sent. Along with your IP address, we collect information regarding which pages you visit on our site, from which page you came to our site, and the software you use to visit our site and its configuration. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. When you use any shopping cart functions that may be included on our websites, your IP address is used to help identify you and your shopping cart and to gather broad demographic information. None of that information is associated with you as an individual.

Our websites also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests. A cookie is a collection of information stored on your computer that usually includes a username and the current date and time or other user specific information that helps us tailor our websites to your interests. Your web browser (Safari, Firefox, Explorer, etc) allows you to be warned when cookies are being placed on your computer or to refuse all cookies. However, not accepting or disabling cookies from our websites may prevent you from accessing certain parts of our websites.

**Information You Provide**  
In addition to information collected by technology, some parts of our websites may ask you to provide personal information. You will know when you are sharing personal information with us because you will need to send a message, fill out a form or application or answer questions, and then agree to provide this information to us. If you choose to share personal information with us, we will use the information only for the purposes you have authorized.

Our site uses online surveys to ask you for information and/or forms for you to request information, products, and services. These online surveys or forms may ask you to provide personal information like contact information (e.g., home or e-mail addresses or phone numbers), unique identifiers (e.g., UM IDs, Social Security numbers), and financial information (e.g., account or credit card numbers). Contact information from these forms is used to respond to requests for information, send orders to you, or to contact you when necessary or requested. You may opt-out of receiving future mailings (see the Choice/Opt-out section below). Financial information that is collected is used to bill you for products and services you have requested. Unique identifiers (such as Social Security numbers) are collected from Web site visitors to verify your identity and for use as account numbers in our record system.

Some of the information we collect or that you provide may be saved for a designated or indefinite period of time, but we will not disclose the information to third parties or government agencies, unless required to do so by state or federal law, in support of University sponsored programs or activities, or to protect the integrity, safety, and security of our websites (see below for information about how to update or remove your information).

**Links Contained on Our Websites**  
This site contains links to other non-University of Miami sites. The University of Miami is not responsible for the privacy practices and/or the content of such websites. Please be sure to check the individual privacy policies of those sites. The University of Miami is also not responsible for the privacy practices and/or content of the University of Miami’s business partners and/or their websites, even if the University of Miami’s brand appears on their page. The University of Miami is not responsible for any information collected by such websites.

**Public Forums**  
This site may make forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to you. Please remember that any information that is disclosed by you or others in these areas is not private and becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information in these or other similar areas of our websites.

**Children’s Guidelines**  
The University of Miami does not knowingly collect online contact information from children under 13 years of age without prior parental consent or parental notification, which will include an opportunity for the parent to prevent use of the information and/or participation in the activity. In the absence of prior parental consent, online information will only be used to respond directly to the child’s request. Such information will not be used for other purposes without prior parental consent. We do not distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information with out prior parental consent. We do not give the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information without prior parental consent. We do not offer special games, prizes or other activities, to entice users to divulge more information than is needed to participate in the activity. We will, however, provide personal information collected about children if required by law, for example, to comply with a court order or a subpoena, or to protect the integrity, safety and security of our websites.

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Our site provides you the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from us when we have requested information about you.  

This site gives you the following options for removing your information from our database in order to avoid receiving future communications or to no longer receive our service:

> 1\. Send e-mail to [webrequest@miami.edu](mailto:webrequest@miami.edu)  
> 2\. Call 305-284-3071

**Correct/Update**  
This site gives you the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided:

> 1\. E-mail [webrequest@miami.edu](mailto:webrequest@miami.edu)  
> 2\. Visit <http://myum.miami.edu/>

**How to Contact Us**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact the University Webmaster, University of Miami, [webmaster@miami.edu](mailto:webmaster@miami.edu).
